THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
FINAL EPISODE
Though I see a future where you live,
it is not guaranteed.
Naturally, if you neglect
the fight for survival, you will die.
But the experience that you'll gain
by going into battle is immeasurable.
I pray for your safe return,
Lord Tokiyuki.
Let the women and children escape first!
If they can escape
through the defensive barriers,
we can hold off
the great enemy army there!
HOSHINA'S ARMY
PROVINCIAL OFFICIAL'S ARMY
Turn around!
We'll defend as one unit
against the enemy from the rear!
Listen, grunts!
The idiots are turning back!
Provincial official's orders!
Kill all the men!
We'll divide the women, children,
and the loot equally!
NANBOKUCHO GAME OF TAG
BURNING DEMON BRIGADE
PROVINCIAL OFFICIAL'S GUARD
HIS FACE LOOKS LIKE THIS
According to Shizuku,
the one named Yonemaru Wada is leading
the provincial official's private force.
A FEW HOURS EARLIER
WITHIN THE HOSHINA PARTY CAMP
If we can just take him down, we'll
weaken the provincial official's army.
Take him down?
You've got it backwards, Kojiro.
First, we'll take advantage of him,
then weaken his army.
Come on! Come on!
Follow me! Climb that mountain!
What?
Weren't we all going to chase down
the Hoshina party together?
You idiots!
We can surround the enemy from behind
if we go over the mountain!
We can annihilate them
with a pincer attack!
Follow me now or I'll kill you, got it?
Yes, sir!
This battle of retreat
will be on flat land.
Tactics like ambushes can't be used,
which puts the outnumbered Hoshina party
at a great disadvantage.
In this case,
we want to divide the enemy's troops.
And one of us has what it takes!
Keep up with Lord Yonemaru!
Keep climbing!
What's happening?
Lord Yonemaru, what is this?
Hey.
-Lord Yonemaru, please direct us!
-Hey… Hey… Hey… Hey?
Hey?
Hey, who am I again?
POP
Who the hell are you?
Hup.
I see. Yesterday, you memorized
how he looks to morph into him.
Mr. Messenger's retainers
aren't too shabby.
I get it.
Kawanakajima's Suwa party are
all highly skilled.
How do you like that, Mr. Messenger?
We're strong when resigned to die,
and we're also strong
when we are willed to live!
Yes.
Even so… Escaping won't be easy.
After the women and children
relocate somewhere safe,
we have to shake off the enemy and escape.
Come to think of it,
where's your vigorous friend?
I've ordered Kojiro
to move of his own accord.
I'm sure he'll be of great help
to you and your men.
I'll perform a hit-and-run.
At my age,
I'm at a disadvantage against adults.
I'll utilize my small stature
to escape to high ground
and seek allies who need my assistance.
I'll deliver an effective blow
then retreat to that high ground.
By repeating this tactic, I've begun
to see the dynamic of the entire battle
and where I should fight next.
I want help from the Hoshina party.
I need four or five men.
Hey, mister! Please come with me!
You, the old man
with focus lines all over your face!
Focus lines all over my face?
Don't make a straight face now.
It's confusing!
You, the geezer with rectangular features
all over, come with me too.
Rectangular features all over?
I guess that's not me then.
Ugh, don't suddenly add round elements!
Now I can't compare you to anything!
What about me?
Compare me to something!
I don't know! You're some kind of monster!
Just come with me!
The enemy is moving along the riverbank
aiming for the women
and children behind us.
Let's band together
and invade them from the side!
Not a damn chance!
Nice work, baldy!
I'm not bald! Take a good look!
Hair grows on the back of my head,
but I shave it off!
You guys are annoying!
Actually, it's my fault
for not remembering my allies' names.
From now on, I'll make
a round of hellos during mealtime.
Fubuki!
Why are you here?
Your waiting post is further that way.
Fubuki!
Fubuki! Get a hold of yourself!
Are you all right? Hey!
I'm so hungry. I can't move.
You're a dumb flake, aren't you?
You sure do need a lot of calories
in exchange for being smart!
Here, take this fresh manju.
All right, I'm recharged and ready to go!
Hurry up and go back to your waiting post.
Please… Isn't your strategy supposed to be
the cornerstone of the Elusive Warriors?
I'm not special.
Anyone can strategize if you just learn.
You run madly around the battlefield,
fighting selflessly,
initiating conversations
and taking care of allies.
It's a general like that who can become
the cornerstone of a party.
Kojiro, you are a solid adjutant general
of the Elusive Warriors.
Being complimented by someone overflowing
with talent only comes across as sarcasm.
Old man with both rectangular
and circular features
and the other guy that's mostly bald
that shaves the little hair
that is growing on the back of his head!
Hey.
You destroyed my independent unit.
You'll meet your end for this.
You're an apprentice
at Suwa Grand Shrine, huh?
Not that it's somethin'
to write home about.
Shut up, pig.
I'll scatter your smelly fat
around Chikuma River.
-Let the best man win!
The top speed for
the fastest native Japanese horses
is about 40 kilometers per hour,
which is roughly the same speed as
the fastest punch of a professional boxer.
This means that just by bracing one's
curved sword and charging on a horse,
a blade is bound to come flying
at the opponent
at the speed of the world's fastest jab.
You're kidding…
Whoa.
What happened, chump?
You talk big,
but are you as puny as you look?
Ha!
We have a difference in strength,
-weight…
-Come on, come on!
-…and relative speed.
-Come at me! Come on!
Come on!
Take this!
I can't even block
his attacks effectively.
Kojiro!
Get back!
You're no physical match on horseback!
Just run!
If I pull out,
it's over for those old geezers.
Yonemaru will remain as
the only one on horseback.
The infantry are
at a complete disadvantage
compared to the cavalry
in terms of speed and strength.
That's why he targeted
the two cavalrymen first.
If I give up now,
that pig will begin his rampage!
He weakens with every attack.
He doesn't have the strength
to block my next strike.
Hey! Kojiro!
Don't worry about me!
Finish the remaining enemy!
Why does everyone know my name anyways?
Oh, that's because Mr. Messenger
kept calling your name yesterday.
Kojiro! Nice, Kojiro!
Don't you dare die!
Look, that's my retainer Kojiro!
That's my friend Kojiro
killing it out there!
So embarrassing…
But…
Kojiro!
I have to get in at least one blow
so that I don't embarrass my lord!
No way.
How did someone so large dodge that?
Damn it… Little bastard!
You think you're a real warrior?
You'll pay for this!
A general who can lead an army
sure is something else…
The spirit of a general
is to be boisterous, huh.
I guess I'll try it next time.
But, damn… My strength… is gone…
Oy, kid.
Don't give out now.
I can't let you die so easily.
First I'll rip your arms off one by one…
You let your guard down
and stopped your horse, didn't you?
You've got nobody to help you now!
Get him, Kojiro!
He's your kill!
Oh, man…
It's fun!
Fighting as a unit is fun!
I am Kojiro of the Elusive Warriors!
I'll take your head and your power!
Take this!
PROVINCIAL OFFICIAL'S MAIN ARMY
Why are you all just standing there?
I can't see through this damn fog!
The enemy's rear guard
is fighting with all their might.
They're stuck in a back-and-forth.
Well, we'll be able to crush them
with our numbers,
though the women and children
will get away at this rate.
What? Chase after them, Ichikawa!
I'll carefully pick my favorite women
to be a part of my paradise!
WOMEN
But if we go, you will be left with no…
There's no need for guards
when the enemy are running away!
Do you not understand military strategy,
you country bumpkin?
OFFICIAL
Is your own life so precious?
If you're a soldier,
go fight with your life on the line!
Tsk.
Great…
Lord Hoshina!
All the women and children
escaped to the safe zone!
Good!
Ring the bell
to signal the army's retreat!
Only the rear guard should stay
to distract the enemy!
Mr. Messenger! You've done enough.
Run!
I cannot, Mr. Hoshina.
I must take responsibility for
instructing you and your men to escape.
It's not right that I come this far
and be the only one who does not taste
the fear of being chased…
Wow…
Mr. Messenger, you care about us so much…
It would be a waste!
Withdraw! Withdraw!
Oy! It's the chime to withdraw. Run!
Okay.
STAB STAB STAB
Hoshina's army has begun to withdraw!
Slice them from behind!
Zigzagging and firing backwards?
I can't move forward easily
with horses and arrows in the way.
That damn brat!
Even though we're almost winning…
Sorry, but I'm not dying
from a fatal shot to my vitals.
Once the enemy begins to think about
the rewards for winning the war,
they will no longer risk their lives
at the front lines.
Furthermore, as for the lord retreating
as the helm of the rear guard,
the most perilous position…
Brilliant! Mr. Messenger.
Mr. Messenger!
…you will earn immense trust
from their allies.
Meanwhile, I'll finish the war
with my own blade!
Crap!
He's aiming for the provincial official!
The blame will fall on me.
They'll kill me!
My provincial official!
Incoming from the right!
What?
That incapable Ichikawa
is screaming something.
He's still chickening out
after coming this far?
Choosing the moment we'd leave
the provincial official's guard!
The morning mist hiding his location!
The army's footsteps masking his approach!
Did he calculate all of this?
Don't come back, coward!
If you don't obey my tactics…
Huh?
My provincial official! Are you all right?
He cut me!
He tried to kill me, the provincial
official appointed by the Emperor!
Killing him would be a poor plan.
An incompetent enemy general
is more useful alive.
My provincial official!
Beyond the river!
There are large shadows of flags!
We don't have allies there!
Another troop coming for my head!
Calm down.
There's no sound of soldiers moving.
They may have just raised flags
to trick us.
You idiot!
It looks like they're about to charge!
Hurry, command Yonemaru's army back here!
Sound the drums to signal withdrawal!
Damn provincial official!
Setaro! Take Yonemaru's place
and lead our soldiers to the front lines!
Sir!
HOSHINA TERRITORY
Once you drive Hoshina beyond his barrier,
build another one of our own
to secure the territory.
PROVINCIAL OFFICIAL'S TERRITORY
Our easy victory is ruined because of him!
This provincial official is
a burden on us.
Tsk.
Oh! The enemy is withdrawing!
Fubuki's strategy was a success!
They'll come to attack us once
they realize the standards are decoys.
Let's run past the barrier while we can!
All right!
My lord!
Kojiro!
-You took quite a while.
-Huh?
You got the kill, right?
Fubuki!
It was amazing.
He took down Yonemaru.
Well done!
Where is his head for proof?
I left him with it.
He taught me a lot.
Even if I did have his head,
you can't give me a reward, right?
Since you just lost half your territory.
Shut up.
It's true.
Anyhow…
Losing has never felt so good.
Lord Hoshina!
Mr. Messenger!
Lord Hoshina, you're safe!
Lord Hoshina did it again!
We lost our territory,
but it's as if we won.
We get to see these smiles
because we escaped and survived.
Afterwards, Hoshina ruled
a small area in northern Shinano,
and he was driven out to the south.
Lords often change
as time passes. However…
Boing.
By skillfully overcoming crises
time and time again,
-the Hoshina party became…
-Good work!
…a resilient feudal lord lineage
that endured until the Meiji era.
And more importantly for Tokiyuki,
they would become a crucial military force
in the nearing uprising.
Please let Myojin know that we,
the Hoshina party,
were saved by Mr. Messenger
and his retainers.
Let him know that we'll treasure
the precious life we were given
whether by losing or escaping, and we
shall dedicate our lives to serve Myojin.
Yes.
GRUMBLE
Mr. Messenger,
please stop by our territory.
We don't have much,
but we want to repay you.
Dinner!
You know, brat,
it's rude to refuse a gift.
I want to return quickly
to let them know we're safe.
Everyone's probably worried.
You can stay here by yourself, you know.
The Young Lord only needs us as guards.
I was given a gift, as well, so…
Tsk. Goody Two-shoes.
Thank you.
Kojiro, Fubuki, Genba.
Oh, I don't need
a thank-you dinner or anything…
Okay!
My lord, you performed brilliantly.
You owe me a lot of money for this war.
Oh, I fell asleep.
Father?
The war is over.
Lord Tokiyuki will return soon.
I'm so glad the Young Lord is safe!
Let's celebrate when he returns.
Yes! Let's make a lot of delicious food!
We have to prepare before he returns.
Let's cook some meat to give him energy.
Don't blow it into too many pieces.
Let's continue to build alliances!
We'll turn samurai who want to die
into samurai who want to live
and fight with us!
Huh?
What happened? Is there an enemy?
What's gotten into you?
There's a rainbow.
Yes, I see it too.
Hey, don't spray it on me.
THE ELUSIVE SAMURAI
Let's go!